YEN-YU (Annie) LAI

Phone: 204-6980351 Email: yenyulai98@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yen-yu-annie-lai-42bb7684/| GitHub: https://github.com/yenyulai |

Summary

Experienced Full-Stack Web Developer with certificate in Full-Stack Web Development from the University of Toronto. I have skillful techniques in both front-end and back-end with creative design ideas. Also, I have more than 2-year experiences of working with database from previous job. In addition, with the instructor, facilitator, and general manager's experience, I get strong communication and interpersonal skill with working partners and client. Strong skills at persuading and delivering projects and products to client in different fields.

Skills

Languages:

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery, Node, MySQL, MongoDB, *Other Computer Techniques:*

Logic-X pro, Garage Band, Sonar, and Microsoft office applications.

Web-Development Experience

Let's go travel Application

Developer

- Used full-stack techniques including Handlebars, JavaScript, Node, MySql, Travis, Jest, Bootstrap to complete a travel web application.
- Retrieved third party data using Zomato and Amadeus API for the app to recommend and display travel information to app. users.
- Solved API problems to optimize the user experience of the App.

Quarantine Match Application

Developer

- Applied full-stack technical skills including HTML, Materialize, Ajax, JavaScript, and jQuery to complete this entertainment application.
- Retrieved third party data using Love Calculator API for the app to recommend and display the love calculation result to the App. users.
- Communicated and solved problems as well as conflicts in git version control system (VCS).

Schedule-Perfect

Developer

- An individual task that aiming on store and display personal schedule in local storage.
- Using Moment API and different color scheme to track time hourly for the App. Users to better track their daily schedule.
- Highlighted Techniques: HTML, Bootstrap CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query.

Other Work Experience

Winplus IELTS

Winnipeg, Manitoba English Instructor Sep 2018 – Present

- Instructed 5 to 10 ESL learning adults in small classes through the use of lectures and activities to accomplish their IELTS training.
- Integrated ESL learning with arts using drawing and music, as well as multimedia to achieve the maximum learning outcome.
- Provided consultation for individual student with customized strategies to create different learning plan and learning goals for ESL leaners.
- Identified and diagnosed ESL students' learning problems and dilemmas to help students optimize their learning strategies.

Gracenote Inc.

Greater China Region

Music Content Editor & Curriculum Designer 2017

Jan 2016 – July

- Designed training modules and curriculum for staff in the Greater China area regarding music data collection and building data infrastructures for all music genres.
- Streamlined and collected metadata feeds of music contents consisting of 3 languages via the company's voice recognition technologies and music-editing applications.
- Designed and Executed workshop on "How To Genre" for colleagues from different department to understand the cutting-age music trend and knowledge of different music type.

Taipei Hwa Kang Art School

Taiwan

Instructor

Sept. 2014 - Jan 2016

- Implemented audio-visual materials to stimulate students' intellectual ability to cognitive development
- Communicated with students, parents, and authorities to maintain the quality of students' learning.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto-School of Continuing Studies

Canada

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate

Sep2020 –Now

University of Manitoba

Canada

Master of Education Specialist in Music

Sep 2017 – May 2020

National Sun Yat-Sen University

Taiwan

Bachelor of Music

June 2008

ADDITIONAL

Instrumental – Performance proficiency in piano, keyboards, saxophone, electronic bass, and erhu